Your college essays can literally be the most important part of your application,
because besides your activity list, colleges actually want to know if you
can express yourself, if you're unique, and if you are someone who is going
to be an asset to their campus.
And that's why essays make such a big difference.
That being said, though, so many people don't know how to write them
because it's genuinely not clear and they're missing out on this huge
opportunity to get thousands of dollars in scholarships for their essays,
or get into their dream schools that otherwise their GPA wouldn't
be able to get them into.
That is why I do one-on-one college essay coaching.
I got into every single college that I applied to, $600,000 in merit
scholarship offers total, a full tuition scholarship to Vanderbilt
because of my essays, because I had good grades, but I didn't have
remarkable extracurriculars, I didn't win any national STEM awards,
I didn't found a nonprofit, or do any sort of advanced research internships.
That is why my essays definitely moved the needle for me.
And since then, I've worked with over a thousand high school students,
helping them write college essays that have gotten them into their dream
schools, like NYU with a full tuition scholarship, Vanderbilt with a scholarship,
UC Berkeley with the Regents scholarship, Cornell, Penn, Dartmouth,
and so many others, and these one-on-one essay calls are meant to get you
unstuck and help you figure out where to go and what to do, whether
you're brainstorming and you need help actually picking a topic, I can
help you, I can walk you through all seven prompts of the Common App
essays and help you land on a topic that I know for sure will stand out
since I've read over a thousand essays myself, or if you already have an idea,
but don't know how to make an outline, I can also help you with that.
I can help you make sure that it's detailed, that it includes things
that admissions officers are going to like, or if you have a draft, I
can read through your draft and give you detailed line-by-line feedback,
help you figure out what to add, what to cut, and how to make it
better so that it actually stands out.
The essay is one of the most important parts of the application, and it is so
important that you get it right, which is why I offer this help to people.
Because the goal is that you leave our call feeling like,
hey, I kind of know what to do now.
And I'm not so worried about this because I know how stressful
senior year can get and how it can feel like you just don't
know where to go or what to do.
That's what my expertise is for.
That being said, if you already just have a draft and you just want
written feedback, I do also offer an asynchronous version of one-on-one
coaching calls where you can just get written edits for me, but if you
would like the most tailored, specific one-on-one live feedback, then these
one-on-one calls are amazing for that.
So if you have any questions, you can email me at
abigaillang at gmail.com before you book, otherwise you
can book right here on this page.
I would love to work with you, and I can't wait to make sure that
you submit your essay feeling ready.